marketrealist.com 2014-12-03

# Privacy Policy: Your Privacy Rights - Market Realist

**  
Effective Date: March 1, 2013  
Last updated: March 1, 2013**

We at Market Realist, Inc. (the “Company” or “we”) are constantly striving to provide excellent service to you, our customers, and business partners, while building a long-lasting relationship with you. To achieve these goals, we occasionally need information supplied by you (“User Information”) when you visit our website (the “Site”).  We take our responsibilities to you seriously and we value your privacy, and accordingly we see it as a principal responsibility to inform you about how we use and protect you User Information.  If you have further questions about our privacy policy, please contact us at privacy@marketrealist.com.

#### User Information

In order to provide you with our content, including Market Realist articles, commentary, market analysis, we may request that you provide us with your first and last name, and e-mail address. We may request that you provide us with additional User Information from time to time.

In the event that you contact us for customer support through the Site, we may also request that you provide additional User Information relevant to the support requested by you.  You are under no obligation to provide such information.  However, we cannot guarantee that we can provide customer support in the event that relevant information related to the use of our products or services is withheld.  We may retain communications relating to customer support, and/or information drawn from such communications, for statistical and/or reference purposes.

In the event that we decide to operate a user forum via the Site, and you decide to participate in that forum, any personal private and/or confidential information that you elect to disclose to other users on the forum shall be disclosed voluntarily and at your own risk.  Such disclosures shall not be considered User Information, and we are not responsible for maintaining the security of any information so disclosed.

In the event that we decide to allow you to create a public profile via the site that is visible to other users, any personal private and/or confidential information that you elect to disclose to other users in your public profile shall be disclosed voluntarily and at your own risk.  Such disclosures shall not be considered User Information, and we are not responsible for maintaining the security of any information so disclosed.

The Company’s web server records visitor IP addresses and domain names for reporting and site usage analysis. This information is reported internally and then purged periodically.

We use cookies to enable you to sign in and to help personalize your experience of the Site. A cookie is a small text file that a web page server places on your hard disk.  A web server assigns cookies uniquely to you and only a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you can read the cookies.  One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time.  For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a website, a cookie helps the website to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Using cookies simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation. When you return to the website, you can retrieve the information you previously provided, so you can easily use the website’s features that you customized.  You have the ability to accept or decline our cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline some or all cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline all cookies, you may not be able to use interactive features of the Site or other websites that depend on cookies.

#### Use and Sharing of User Information

User Information may be compiled into user profiles that are maintained by Company (or by third party services used by the Company to manage customer information), and may be used for the following purposes:

  * To send you an e-mail communication for the purposes of validating your registration with the Site
  * To verify the information that you have provided during registration in order to verify your qualifications to access the Site
  * To send you information about Company, product updates, special offers, and newsletters
  * To provide customer support for Company products and services
  * To initiate or to respond  to a subpoena, investigative demand, or other discovery request that is properly served pursuant to state or federal law
  * To take actions necessary to protect and/or to defend Company’s rights and property (including intellectual property)
  * To protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site

User Information may be shared with:

  * Third party services that we use to manage customer information
  * Third parties with whom we partner to enhance the products or services that we provide
  * Third parties for the purpose of verifying your qualifications to access the Site
  * Government agencies (including courts and law enforcement agencies)
  * Parties to civil or criminal litigation or arbitration (including arbitrators and/or mediators involved in litigation or arbitration)

We will not provide User Information to third parties used to manage customer information, or with whom we partner to enhance products or services, unless we receive assurances from such third party that it (1) will not use or disclose User Information for purposes of solicitation or direct marketing, and (2) will keep User Information secure using methods comparable to, or more secure than, the security methods used by Company.  However, we do not control third parties, and we assume no liability in the event that a third party breaches its promises regarding confidentiality.  We encourage you to contact us at privacy@marketrealist.com if you suspect that your User Information has been compromised by a third party.

To the extent that you provide User Information to us concerning third parties, including information regarding your employer, that information will be subject to the same conditions as set forth above.

#### Information Obtained from Children Under 13 Years of Age

Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Privacy Policy, the following terms shall apply to User Information obtained from users under the age of 13 years (“Junior Users”).  For the purposes of this section, the term “Personal Information” means individually identifiable information about an individual collected online, including:

(A) a first and last name;  
(B) a home or other physical address including street name and name of a city or town;  
(C) an e-mail address;  
(D) a telephone number;  
(E) a Social Security number;  
(F) any other identifier that the Federal Trade Commission shall determine permits the physical or online contacting of a specific individual; or  
(G) information concerning a Junior User or the parent or legal guardian of that Junior User that Company collects online from the Junior User and combines with an identifier described in (A) through (F) above.

Upon request of the parent or legal guardian of a Junior User, Company will, upon verification of the identity of the parent, provide the parent or legal guardian:

  * a description of the specific types of Personal Information collected from the Junior User
  * any Personal Information collected from the Junior User

The parent or legal guardian of a Junior User may request the information described above by contacting Company by mail at Market Realist Inc. 447 Broadway, 2nd Floor New York, NY 10013, or by e-mail at privacy@marketrealist.com.

Upon request of the parent or legal guardian of a Junior User, Company will cease to use, or to maintain in retrievable form, any Personal Information collected from that Junior User, and will not collect any further Personal Information from that Junior User.  Upon such a request, Company reserves the right to terminate the registration of the Junior User, and/or terminate and/or limit the Junior User’s access to the Site.

Company does not condition participation by Junior Users in any game, opportunity to win a prize, or other activity, upon the Junior User disclosing more Personal Information than is reasonably necessary to participate in that activity.

Company has established and maintains procedures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of the Personal Information collected from Junior Users, just as it protects the User Information provided by all of its users.  The methods used to protect this information are described below.

Company reserves the right to collect, to use, and to disclose Personal Information as and when necessary:

  * to protect the security or integrity of the Site;
  * to take precautions against liability;
  * to respond to judicial process; or
  * to the extent permitted under other provisions of law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation on a matter related to public safety.

#### Right to Review, Correct and Delete User Information

If you provide us with User Information, you have the following rights with respect to that information:

  * To review the User Information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that we correct any errors, outdated information, or omissions in User Information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that your User Information not be used to contact you
  * To request that your User Information be removed from any solicitation list that we use
  * To request that your User Information be deleted from our records
  * To opt out of being solicited by the Company or by third parties

If you request that your User Information be deleted from our records, there may be a brief delay in our processing that request while we verify that the request is valid and originates from you as opposed to an unauthorized third party.  If you request that your User Information be deleted, we reserve the right to terminate and/or limit your access to the Site. To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at privacy@marketrealist.com.

#### Security Measures

No method of safeguarding information is 100% secure.  We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect User Information from unauthorized and improper access, use, disclosure, modification, and destruction. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities.

Within the Company, we restrict access to User Information to individuals who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our products or services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

**Links to Other Sites  
**Our Site contains links to other Web sites, including our partners and media websites. Please be aware that our privacy policy does not apply to these other sites.

#### Third Party Advertisers

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Site. These companies may use information (including any Personal Information) about web activity in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. The use of these technologies by third party advertising companies is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please contact us if you would like to know the identity of the third party advertising companies we use to serve ads.

#### Changes to Policy

Company will occasionally update this privacy policy. When we do, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of the privacy policy. YOU WILL BE PROVIDED NOTICE OF ANY CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AND THE OPPORTUNITY TO REVIEW ANY SUCH CHANGES.  YOU WILL BE REQUIRED TO ACCEPT ANY SUCH CHANGES IN ORDER TO CONTINUE USING THE SITE.  YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE SITE CONSTITUTES ACCEPTANCE OF ANY AMENDED TERMS.

Company keeps prior versions of this Privacy Policy for five (5) years from the date of the most recent update.  Prior versions of the Privacy Policy are available upon request to privacy@marketrealist.com.

#### Enforcement of This Privacy Statement

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact us at privacy@marketrealist.com.  If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or we have not addressed your inquiry to your satisfaction, you should then contact us via our web form at <http://marketrealist.com/contact/>.

#### Contact Information

We welcome your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us by email at privacy@marketrealist.com.

Our address is:  
Market Realist Inc.  
447 Broadway  
2nd Floor  
New York, NY 10013
